[
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00000",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "New York",
                "subject": "Jennifer Lynn Lopez"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "July 24, 1969",
                "subject": "Jennifer Lynn Lopez"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Guadalupe Rodriguez",
                "subject": "Jennifer Lynn Lopez"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "David Lopez",
                "subject": "Jennifer Lynn Lopez"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Jennifer",
                    "jennifer",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "Lynn",
                    "lynn",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "Lopez",
                    "lopez",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "on",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "July",
                    "july",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "24",
                    "24",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "1969",
                    "1969",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "the",
                    "the",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    "Castle",
                    "castle",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-LOCATION"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "Hill",
                    "hill",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-LOCATION"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    "neighborhood",
                    "neighborhood",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    "of",
                    "of",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    "The",
                    "the",
                    "DT",
                    "B-WORK_OF_ART"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "Bronx",
                    "bronx",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-WORK_OF_ART"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    21,
                    "New",
                    "new",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    22,
                    "York",
                    "york",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    23,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    24,
                    "to",
                    "to",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    25,
                    "Puerto",
                    "puerto",
                    "JJ",
                    "B-NORP"
                ],
                [
                    26,
                    "Rican",
                    "rican",
                    "JJ",
                    "I-NORP"
                ],
                [
                    27,
                    "parents",
                    "parent",
                    "NNS",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    28,
                    "Guadalupe",
                    "guadalupe",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    29,
                    "Rodriguez",
                    "rodriguez",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    30,
                    "and",
                    "and",
                    "CC",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    31,
                    "David",
                    "david",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    32,
                    "Lopez",
                    "lopez",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    33,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Jennifer Lynn Lopez was born on July 24, 1969, in the Castle Hill neighborhood of The Bronx, New York, to Puerto Rican parents Guadalupe Rodriguez and David Lopez."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00001",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "June 6, 1960",
                "subject": "Steve Vai"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "New York",
                "subject": "Steve Vai"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Carle Place",
                "subject": "Steve Vai"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Steve",
                    "steve",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "Vai",
                    "vai",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "a",
                    "a",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "descendant",
                    "descendant",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "of",
                    "of",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "Italian",
                    "italian",
                    "JJ",
                    "B-NORP"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "immigrants",
                    "immigrant",
                    "NNS",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "Carle",
                    "carle",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-LOCATION"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    "Place",
                    "place",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-LOCATION"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    "New",
                    "new",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    "York",
                    "york",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    "on",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "June",
                    "june",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    "6",
                    "6",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    21,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    22,
                    "1960",
                    "1960",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    23,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Steve Vai, a descendant of Italian immigrants, was born in Carle Place, New York on June 6, 1960."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00002",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Houston",
                "subject": "John Dickson \"Peck\" Kelley"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Texas",
                "subject": "John Dickson \"Peck\" Kelley"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "October 22, 1898",
                "subject": "John Dickson \"Peck\" Kelley"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "John",
                    "john",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "Dickson",
                    "dickson",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "\"",
                    "\"",
                    "``",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "Peck",
                    "peck",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "\"",
                    "\"",
                    "''",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "Kelley",
                    "kelley",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "Houston",
                    "houston",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "Texas",
                    "texas",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "on",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    "October",
                    "october",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "22",
                    "22",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    "1898",
                    "1898",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "John Dickson \"Peck\" Kelley was born in Houston, Texas on October 22, 1898. "
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00003",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Arizona",
                "subject": "Hernandez"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Nogales",
                "subject": "Hernandez"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "1957",
                "subject": "Hernandez"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Hernandez",
                    "hernandez",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "Nogales",
                    "nogales",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "Arizona",
                    "arizona",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "1957",
                    "1957",
                    "CD",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "and",
                    "and",
                    "CC",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "is",
                    "be",
                    "VBZ",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "of",
                    "of",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    "Hispanic",
                    "hispanic",
                    "JJ",
                    "B-NORP"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "descent",
                    "descent",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Hernandez was born in Nogales, Arizona, in 1957 and is of Hispanic descent."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00004",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Fausta Genoveva Sanchez Rivera",
                "subject": "Del Toro"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "San German",
                "subject": "Del Toro"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Gustavo Adolfo Del Toro Bermudez",
                "subject": "Del Toro"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "February 19, 1967",
                "subject": "Del Toro"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Puerto Rico",
                "subject": "Del Toro"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Del",
                    "del",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "Toro",
                    "toro",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "on",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "February",
                    "february",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "19",
                    "19",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    "1967",
                    "1967",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "San",
                    "san",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "German",
                    "german",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "Puerto",
                    "puerto",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    "Rico",
                    "rico",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    "to",
                    "to",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "Gustavo",
                    "gustavo",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    "Adolfo",
                    "adolfo",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    21,
                    "Del",
                    "del",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    22,
                    "Toro",
                    "toro",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    23,
                    "Bermudez",
                    "bermudez",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    24,
                    "and",
                    "and",
                    "CC",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    25,
                    "Fausta",
                    "fausta",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    26,
                    "Genoveva",
                    "genoveva",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    27,
                    "Sanchez",
                    "sanchez",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    28,
                    "Rivera",
                    "rivera",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    29,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    30,
                    "who",
                    "who",
                    "WP",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    31,
                    "were",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    32,
                    "both",
                    "both",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    33,
                    "lawyers",
                    "lawyer",
                    "NNS",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    34,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Del Toro was born on February 19, 1967, in San German, Puerto Rico, to Gustavo Adolfo Del Toro Bermudez and Fausta Genoveva Sanchez Rivera, who were both lawyers."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00005",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Mount Willing",
                "subject": "Moorer"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "February 9, 1912",
                "subject": "Moorer"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Alabama",
                "subject": "Moorer"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Moorer",
                    "moorer",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "Mount",
                    "mount",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-LOCATION"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "Willing",
                    "willing",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-LOCATION"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "Alabama",
                    "alabama",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    "on",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "February",
                    "february",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "9",
                    "9",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "1912",
                    "1912",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Moorer was born in Mount Willing, Alabama on February 9, 1912."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00006",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "August 14, 1822",
                "subject": "James William Marshall"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Virginia",
                "subject": "James William Marshall"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Clarke County",
                "subject": "James William Marshall"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "James",
                    "james",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "William",
                    "william",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "Marshall",
                    "marshall",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "Clarke",
                    "clarke",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "County",
                    "county",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "Virginia",
                    "virginia",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "on",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "August",
                    "august",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    "14",
                    "14",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    "1822",
                    "1822",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "James William Marshall was born in Clarke County, Virginia, on August 14, 1822."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00007",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "St Louis",
                "subject": "Wood"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "AlternateName",
                "object": "Bradshaw",
                "subject": "Mary"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Thomas Frank Wood",
                "subject": "Wood"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Mary",
                "subject": "Wood"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Missouri",
                "subject": "Wood"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "September 16, 1923",
                "subject": "Wood"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Wood",
                    "wood",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "on",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "September",
                    "september",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "16",
                    "16",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "1923",
                    "1923",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "St",
                    "st",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "Louis",
                    "louis",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "Missouri",
                    "missouri",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "the",
                    "the",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    "son",
                    "son",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    "of",
                    "of",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    "Mary",
                    "mary",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "(",
                    "(",
                    "-LRB-",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    "nee",
                    "nee",
                    "FW",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    21,
                    "Bradshaw",
                    "bradshaw",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    22,
                    ")",
                    ")",
                    "-RRB-",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    23,
                    "Wood",
                    "wood",
                    "NNP",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    24,
                    "and",
                    "and",
                    "CC",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    25,
                    "Thomas",
                    "thomas",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    26,
                    "Frank",
                    "frank",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    27,
                    "Wood",
                    "wood",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    28,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Wood was born on September 16, 1923 in St Louis, Missouri, the son of Mary (nee Bradshaw) Wood and Thomas Frank Wood."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00008",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "May 27, 1936",
                "subject": "Gossett"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Sheepshead Bay",
                "subject": "Gossett"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "New York",
                "subject": "Gossett"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Hellen Rebecca",
                "subject": "Gossett"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "AlternateName",
                "object": "Hellen Rebecca",
                "subject": "Wray"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Brooklyn",
                "subject": "Gossett"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Louis Gossett Sr.",
                "subject": "Gossett"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Gossett",
                    "gossett",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "Sheepshead",
                    "sheepshead",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "Bay",
                    "bay",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "Brooklyn",
                    "brooklyn",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "New",
                    "new",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "York",
                    "york",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "on",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    "May",
                    "may",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "27",
                    "27",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    "1936",
                    "1936",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "to",
                    "to",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    "Hellen",
                    "hellen",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    21,
                    "Rebecca",
                    "rebecca",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    22,
                    "(",
                    "(",
                    "-LRB-",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    23,
                    "nee",
                    "nee",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    24,
                    "Wray",
                    "wray",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    25,
                    ")",
                    ")",
                    "-RRB-",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    26,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    27,
                    "a",
                    "a",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    28,
                    "nurse",
                    "nurse",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    29,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    30,
                    "and",
                    "and",
                    "CC",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    31,
                    "Louis",
                    "louis",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    32,
                    "Gossett",
                    "gossett",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    33,
                    "Sr",
                    "sr",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    34,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    35,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    36,
                    "a",
                    "a",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    37,
                    "porter",
                    "porter",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    38,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Gossett was born in Sheepshead Bay, Brooklyn, New York, on May 27, 1936, to Hellen Rebecca (nee Wray), a nurse, and Louis Gossett Sr., a porter."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00009",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "New York City",
                "subject": "Arthur Allen Cohen"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "1928",
                "subject": "Arthur Allen Cohen"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Bess Junger Cohen",
                "subject": "Arthur Allen Cohen"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Isidore Meyer",
                "subject": "Arthur Allen Cohen"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "New",
                    "new",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "York",
                    "york",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "City",
                    "city",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "1928",
                    "1928",
                    "CD",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    "Arthur",
                    "arthur",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "Allen",
                    "allen",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "Cohen",
                    "cohen",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "the",
                    "the",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    "son",
                    "son",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "of",
                    "of",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    "Isidore",
                    "isidore",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    "Meyer",
                    "meyer",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    "and",
                    "and",
                    "CC",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "Bess",
                    "bess",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    "Junger",
                    "junger",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    21,
                    "Cohen",
                    "cohen",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    22,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    23,
                    "both",
                    "both",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    24,
                    "second",
                    "second",
                    "JJ",
                    "B-ORDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    25,
                    "-",
                    "-",
                    "HYPH",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    26,
                    "generation",
                    "generation",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    27,
                    "Americans",
                    "americans",
                    "NNPS",
                    "B-NORP"
                ],
                [
                    28,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Born in New York City in 1928, Arthur Allen Cohen was the son of Isidore Meyer and Bess Junger Cohen, both second-generation Americans."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00010",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "June 12, 1992",
                "subject": "Malgarini"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Renton",
                "subject": "Malgarini"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "AlternateName",
                "object": "Ryan Timothy Malgarini",
                "subject": "Malgarini"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Washington",
                "subject": "Malgarini"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Malgarini",
                    "malgarini",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "Ryan",
                    "ryan",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "Timothy",
                    "timothy",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "Malgarini",
                    "malgarini",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "Renton",
                    "renton",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "Washington",
                    "washington",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "on",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "June",
                    "june",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "12",
                    "12",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "1992",
                    "1992",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Malgarini was born Ryan Timothy Malgarini in Renton, Washington on June 12, 1992."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00011",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Quitman County",
                "subject": "Earl Zebedee Hooker"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Mississippi",
                "subject": "Earl Zebedee Hooker"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "January 15, 1929",
                "subject": "Earl Zebedee Hooker"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Earl",
                    "earl",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "Zebedee",
                    "zebedee",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "Hooker",
                    "hooker",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "on",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "January",
                    "january",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "15",
                    "15",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "1929",
                    "1929",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "rural",
                    "rural",
                    "JJ",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    "Quitman",
                    "quitman",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "County",
                    "county",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    "Mississippi",
                    "mississippi",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "outside",
                    "outside",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    "of",
                    "of",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    21,
                    "Clarksdale",
                    "clarksdale",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    22,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Earl Zebedee Hooker was born on January 15, 1929, in rural Quitman County, Mississippi, outside of Clarksdale."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00012",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Elizabeth",
                "subject": "Catherine Bauer"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Jacob Bauer",
                "subject": "Catherine Bauer"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "May 11, 1905",
                "subject": "Catherine Bauer"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "New Jersey",
                "subject": "Catherine Bauer"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Alberta Krause Bauer",
                "subject": "Catherine Bauer"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "On",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "May",
                    "may",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "11",
                    "11",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "1905",
                    "1905",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "Catherine",
                    "catherine",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "Bauer",
                    "bauer",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "Elizabeth",
                    "elizabeth",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    "New",
                    "new",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "Jersey",
                    "jersey",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    "to",
                    "to",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    "Alberta",
                    "alberta",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    "Krause",
                    "krause",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "Bauer",
                    "bauer",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    21,
                    "a",
                    "a",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    22,
                    "self",
                    "self",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    23,
                    "-",
                    "-",
                    "HYPH",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    24,
                    "educated",
                    "educate",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    25,
                    "homemaker",
                    "homemaker",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    26,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    27,
                    "and",
                    "and",
                    "CC",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    28,
                    "Jacob",
                    "jacob",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    29,
                    "Bauer",
                    "bauer",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    30,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "On May 11, 1905, Catherine Bauer was born in Elizabeth, New Jersey to Alberta Krause Bauer, a self-educated homemaker, and Jacob Bauer."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00013",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Joyce Shuler",
                "subject": "Liz Shuler"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "1970",
                "subject": "Liz Shuler"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Lance",
                "subject": "Liz Shuler"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Liz",
                    "liz",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "Shuler",
                    "shuler",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "to",
                    "to",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "Lance",
                    "lance",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "and",
                    "and",
                    "CC",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "Joyce",
                    "joyce",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    "Shuler",
                    "shuler",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "1970",
                    "1970",
                    "CD",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Liz Shuler was born to Lance and Joyce Shuler in 1970."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00014",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Joseph Momoa",
                "subject": "Momoa"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Honolulu",
                "subject": "Momoa"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Hawaii",
                "subject": "Momoa"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "1979",
                "subject": "Momoa"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "HasParent",
                "object": "Coni",
                "subject": "Momoa"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "An",
                    "an",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "only",
                    "only",
                    "JJ",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "child",
                    "child",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "Momoa",
                    "momoa",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    "Honolulu",
                    "honolulu",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "Hawaii",
                    "hawaii",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "1979",
                    "1979",
                    "CD",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "to",
                    "to",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    "Coni",
                    "coni",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    "a",
                    "a",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "photographer",
                    "photographer",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    21,
                    "and",
                    "and",
                    "CC",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    22,
                    "Joseph",
                    "joseph",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    23,
                    "Momoa",
                    "momoa",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    24,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    25,
                    "a",
                    "a",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    26,
                    "painter",
                    "painter",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    27,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "An only child, Momoa was born in Honolulu, Hawaii in 1979, to Coni, a photographer, and Joseph Momoa, a painter."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00015",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Indiana",
                "subject": "Joseph A. Garcia"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "March 21, 1957",
                "subject": "Joseph A. Garcia"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Lafayette",
                "subject": "Joseph A. Garcia"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Joseph",
                    "joseph",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "A.",
                    "a.",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "Garcia",
                    "garcia",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "was",
                    "be",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "on",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "March",
                    "march",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "21",
                    "21",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "1957",
                    "1957",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "Lafayette",
                    "lafayette",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "Indiana",
                    "indiana",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Joseph A. Garcia was born on March 21, 1957, in Lafayette, Indiana."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00016",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "LifeSpan",
                "object": "1871-1918",
                "subject": "Van Meter"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "LifeSpan",
                "object": "1872-1924",
                "subject": "Julia Miller"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Van",
                    "van",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "Meter",
                    "meter",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "(",
                    "(",
                    "-LRB-",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "1871",
                    "1871",
                    "CD",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "-",
                    "-",
                    "SYM",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "1918",
                    "1918",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    ")",
                    ")",
                    "-RRB-",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "&",
                    "&",
                    "CC",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    "Julia",
                    "julia",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "Miller",
                    "miller",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "(",
                    "(",
                    "-LRB-",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "1872",
                    "1872",
                    "CD",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "-",
                    "-",
                    "SYM",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    "1924",
                    "1924",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    ")",
                    ")",
                    "-RRB-",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    "1905",
                    "1905",
                    "CD",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    "(",
                    "(",
                    "-LRB-",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "according",
                    "accord",
                    "VBG",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    "to",
                    "to",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    21,
                    "other",
                    "other",
                    "JJ",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    22,
                    "sources",
                    "source",
                    "NNS",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    23,
                    "December",
                    "december",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    24,
                    "3",
                    "3",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    25,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    26,
                    "1906",
                    "1906",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    27,
                    ")",
                    ")",
                    "-RRB-",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    28,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    29,
                    "Fort",
                    "fort",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    30,
                    "Wayne",
                    "wayne",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    31,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    32,
                    "Indiana",
                    "indiana",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    33,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    34,
                    "the",
                    "the",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    35,
                    "son",
                    "son",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    36,
                    "of",
                    "of",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    37,
                    "an",
                    "an",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    38,
                    "alcoholic",
                    "alcoholic",
                    "JJ",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    39,
                    "railroad",
                    "railroad",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    40,
                    "conductor",
                    "conductor",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    41,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Van Meter (1871-1918) & Julia Miller (1872-1924) in 1905 (according to other sources December 3, 1906) in Fort Wayne, Indiana, the son of an alcoholic railroad conductor."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00017",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "February 24, 1978",
                "subject": "Shannon"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "PlaceOfBirth",
                "object": "Oklahoma",
                "subject": "Shannon"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Born",
                    "bear",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "Oklahoma",
                    "oklahoma",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "on",
                    "on",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "February",
                    "february",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "24",
                    "24",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "1978",
                    "1978",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "Shannon",
                    "shannon",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "earned",
                    "earn",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "a",
                    "a",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "Bachelor",
                    "bachelor",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-ORG"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    "of",
                    "of",
                    "IN",
                    "I-ORG"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "Arts",
                    "arts",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-ORG"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    "degree",
                    "degree",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    "in",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    "communications",
                    "communication",
                    "NNS",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "from",
                    "from",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    "Cameron",
                    "cameron",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-ORG"
                ],
                [
                    21,
                    "University",
                    "university",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-ORG"
                ],
                [
                    22,
                    "and",
                    "and",
                    "CC",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    23,
                    "holds",
                    "hold",
                    "VBZ",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    24,
                    "a",
                    "a",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    25,
                    "Juris",
                    "juris",
                    "NNP",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    26,
                    "Doctor",
                    "doctor",
                    "NNP",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    27,
                    "from",
                    "from",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    28,
                    "Oklahoma",
                    "oklahoma",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    29,
                    "City",
                    "city",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-GPE"
                ],
                [
                    30,
                    "University",
                    "university",
                    "NNP",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    31,
                    "Law",
                    "law",
                    "NNP",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    32,
                    "School",
                    "school",
                    "NNP",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    33,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "Born in Oklahoma on February 24, 1978, Shannon earned a Bachelor of Arts degree in communications from Cameron University and holds a Juris Doctor from Oklahoma City University Law School."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00018",
        "relations": [],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "In",
                    "in",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "1904",
                    "1904",
                    "CD",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "the",
                    "the",
                    "DT",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "wealthy",
                    "wealthy",
                    "JJ",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "family",
                    "family",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "grew",
                    "grow",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "destitute",
                    "destitute",
                    "JJ",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    "after",
                    "after",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "Holman",
                    "holman",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "'s",
                    "'s",
                    "POS",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "uncle",
                    "uncle",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "Ross",
                    "ross",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    "Holzman",
                    "holzman",
                    "NNP",
                    "I-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "embezzled",
                    "embezzle",
                    "VBD",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    "nearly",
                    "nearly",
                    "RB",
                    "B-MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    "$",
                    "$",
                    "$",
                    "I-MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    "1",
                    "1",
                    "CD",
                    "I-MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "million",
                    "million",
                    "CD",
                    "I-MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    "of",
                    "of",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    21,
                    "their",
                    "their",
                    "PRP$",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    22,
                    "stock",
                    "stock",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    23,
                    "brokerage",
                    "brokerage",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    24,
                    "business",
                    "business",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    25,
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    ".",
                    "O"
                ]
            ],
            "text": "In 1904, the wealthy family grew destitute after Holman's uncle Ross Holzman embezzled nearly $1 million of their stock brokerage business."
        }
    },
    {
        "sentence_id": "TR.00019",
        "relations": [
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "January 10, 1924",
                "subject": "Roach"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "AlternateName",
                "object": "Roach",
                "subject": "Roach"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "DateOfBirth",
                "object": "January 8, 1925",
                "subject": "Roach"
            },
            {
                "predicate": "AlternateName",
                "object": "Roach",
                "subject": "Phil Schaap"
            }
        ],
        "sentence": {
            "annotation": [
                [
                    1,
                    "Although",
                    "although",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    2,
                    "Roach",
                    "roach",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    3,
                    "'s",
                    "'s",
                    "POS",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    4,
                    "birth",
                    "birth",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    5,
                    "certificate",
                    "certificate",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    6,
                    "lists",
                    "list",
                    "VBZ",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    7,
                    "his",
                    "his",
                    "PRP$",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    8,
                    "date",
                    "date",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    9,
                    "of",
                    "of",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    10,
                    "birth",
                    "birth",
                    "NN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    11,
                    "as",
                    "as",
                    "IN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    12,
                    "January",
                    "january",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    13,
                    "10",
                    "10",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    14,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    15,
                    "1924",
                    "1924",
                    "CD",
                    "I-DATE"
                ],
                [
                    16,
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    ",",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    17,
                    "Roach",
                    "roach",
                    "NNP",
                    "B-PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    18,
                    "has",
                    "have",
                    "VBZ",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    19,
                    "been",
                    "be",
                    "VBN",
                    "O"
                ],
                [
                    20,
                    "quoted",
                    "quote",
                    "VBN",
